There are only a few truly pleasant smells to wake up to in the morning.
早上能让人醒来后感到愉悦的气味其实没几种。
It might be the aroma of freshly baked bread, or the scent of your partner's freshly brushed teeth – but for me, it's the smell of freshly brewed coffee.
可能是刚烤好的面包香气，也可能是伴侣刚刷完牙的清新气息——但对我来说，是现煮咖啡的香味。
Just a sniff of it makes me jump out of bed and rush to the kitchen for a gulp of the hot black liquid.
只要闻一下，我就会从床上跳起来，冲到厨房喝一大口热黑咖啡。
But then things quickly go downhill.
但接下来事情就急转直下了。
If you're a coffee connoisseur, you'll understand that opening a new packet of coffee releases an amazing smell – fresh, roasted coffee beans. Delicious!
如果你是咖啡鉴赏家，就会知道打开一包新咖啡时，会散发出惊人的香气——那是新鲜烘焙咖啡豆的味道，太美味了！
And if you've got a nose for the stuff, you'll be able to identify the beans' origin – Colombia, Vietnam or maybe Brazil – the world's biggest coffee producer.
要是你的鼻子对咖啡的味道很敏感，还能分辨出咖啡豆的产地——哥伦比亚、越南，或者可能是巴西，这个世界上最大的咖啡生产国。
Tim Hayward is a food writer and coffee shop owner; he told the BBC that the smell "is absolutely vital, it's the key thing.
蒂姆·海沃德是美食作家，也是咖啡店老板，他告诉英国广播公司：“气味至关重要，是核心所在。
And when you walk into the coffee shop in the morning and that smell hits you, you're getting physiological responses."
当你早上走进咖啡店，闻到那股香味时，你的身体会产生生理反应。”
I know from experience when I walk into a cafe for my double espresso or flat white, my mouth begins to water in anticipation.
从我的个人经历我知道，当我走进咖啡店点双倍浓缩咖啡或白咖啡时，期待感会让我流口水。
Although it's really the caffeine hit I'm after, it's the smell that makes me feel good.
虽然我真正追求的是咖啡因带来的提神效果，但那股香味才是让我心情愉悦的关键。
However, this feeling sometimes turns to disappointment when I actually start drinking my hot beverage – the taste just doesn't match the smell.
然而，当我真正开始喝这杯热饮时，这种愉悦感有时会让我很失望——味道和香味完全不匹配。
This is particularly the case when I order a coffee to go in a tall paper cup and sip the liquid through a hole in the lid.
尤其是点外带咖啡时，装在高高的纸杯里，透过杯盖上的小孔喝，这种感觉更明显。
Yes, it's convenient, but is it really the right way to appreciate it?
没错，这样很方便，但这真的是品鉴咖啡的正确方式吗？
Tim Hayward describes this process as 'weird' and 'baffling'.
蒂姆·海沃德把这个过程形容为“怪异”且“令人困惑”。
He says, "You walk into the coffee shop, you get the smell, but when you actually take the drink out, you are drinking it from something that is designed to deliver the hot liquid directly past your tongue, but stop any smell coming up to your nose."
他说：“你走进咖啡店，闻到了香味，但当你把咖啡外带时，盛咖啡的容器设计成能让热饮直接流过舌头，却阻止了任何气味传到鼻子里。”
As well as eliminating the smell, takeaway coffee cups create a lot of waste and a vast majority of them still don't get recycled.
除了隔绝香味，外带咖啡杯还产生了大量垃圾，而且绝大多数仍然无法回收。
In 2011, it was estimated that 2.5 billion coffee cups were thrown away each year in the UK, and that figure is likely to be higher now.
2011年，据估计英国每年会丢弃25亿个咖啡杯，现在这个数字可能更高了。
So maybe now is the time to really wake up and smell the coffee by drinking from a cup or mug in a cafe, chatting with friends and saving the planet!
所以，或许现在是时候真正“清醒过来，品味咖啡”了——在咖啡店里用杯子或马克杯喝咖啡，和朋友聊天，同时保护地球！